what's up everybody this is Nick at
bobbend.com and today we are talking
about the best creatine supplements on
the market that's right it's creatine it
is absolutely everywhere the reason is
it works it is one of the most
thoroughly researched Sports supplements
out there probably the most early
research to be honest unless you're
counting protein creatine has
unbelievably strong links like we're
talking hundreds and hundreds of studies
very strong links with increased power
output and aesthetically bigger muscles
as well but you might not know that
there are also some links potentially
for mental benefits a little bit later
in life and a little bit later in this
video we're going to get into that a bit
later on we're going to be talking about
in this video a wide variety of good
creatine products including the best
creative team for beginners the best for
bulking the best creatine hydrochloride
and more so absolutely make sure you
stick around because you're going to
learn a lot about creatine today I
should make it clear and then a doctor
this is not medical advice that's always
important to remember when you are
reading or watching information about
supplements on the internet for medical
advice you've got to go to your doctor
so if you think making any changes to
your supplement or nutrition or exercise
regimen be sure to talk to a qualified
medical professional to make sure that
it all squares away with you your
personal history your medications and
also that kind of stuff that's
individual just to you so what's the
best creation on the market it's
Wolverine's creation monohydrate why
because it's creatine monohydrate you
don't need that many bells and muscles
with creatine a lot of people add them
in and they can have their use and we're
going to talk about to them a little bit
later on but if we've got any best
creatine on the market we just want
someone who's given you plain unflavored
good quality American made creatine
monohydrate that's Wolverine yes it is
made in America in acetified good
manufacturing practices facility to boot
real easy unflavored mix it into your
drinks dry scuba whatever you want to do
it's unflavored it doesn't really taste
like anything you can do whatever you
want sprinkle it over your meat as
though it's salt if you like you won't
tasted creatine monohydrate best a glass
of water there so what is creatine I
mean it's both pretty complicated and
pretty simple but it's an organic
compound nitrogenous organic compound
sometimes called I mean no acid
sometimes called an amino acid
derivative all you need to know is that
it is plain white powder right creatine
is found naturally in Foods uh most
famously red meat also in smaller
amounts in like chicken and poultry and
fish as well and as I mentioned earlier
at this point countless Studies have
found to have an effect on power output
sometimes anywhere from 10 to 22 percent
that's very high uh it probably would be
22 for everybody but nonetheless uh
they're pretty concrete and reliable
results for these sorts of studies so
that's the athletic reason you'd want to
get an increased power output doesn't
just seem like a heavier bench it could
mean like better sprinting and so on in
the one to three rep range in particular
is where creatine is missing tablet's
most ergogenic effect effects like that
the other thing I want to mention on the
benefits of creatine it really is power
output is aesthetic benefits You could
argue it has hydration benefits as well
and also if you don't eat much meat
there are potentially mental benefits to
having creatine namely research has
found that among vegetarians and also
among older folks who tend to not eat as
much meat or as much protein
supplementing creatine can help to
improve memory and the good news is
although creatine is only found in
animals in the real world creating like
this like in powdered form uh it's
perfectly vegan vegetarian friendly so
plenty of good reasons to get creatine
into your diet if you eat plenty of meat
probably there's mental benefits aren't
going to be a big deal but it's worth
noting that creation does play an
important role in energy production not
just in your muscles but also in your
brain
[Music]
as mentioned before Wolverines creation
monohydrate is our favorite creatine
product and we name you the best for a
whole lot of categories because it is
regular it creates the monohydrate with
absolutely nothing else so it's really
easy to say that Wolverines creatine
monohydrate is the best overall let's
just creatine it's also the best for men
it's also the best for cutting that's
how creatine works because in both
instances you're really just going to
want regular creatine monohydrate right
and you can just get other supplements
around that again there's nothing wrong
with having creatine products that have
extra supplements and extra ingredients
on the nutrition profile but if you just
want regular crazy amount of hydrate as
mentioned before that is all this is it
is 5 000 milligrams per scoop that is
the normal cervix to have people
generally take five grams a day
sometimes three but typically five grams
a day for about four weeks then you get
all saturated and you get all these
benefits of creatine it is non-GMO vegan
gluten free and also made in the US in a
good manufacturing practices certified
facility so it's really all you could
want from a creatine when I hydrate just
watch on some of the stuff I said
earlier uh it's a great creatine for
muscle growth because creatine is very
good at producing muscle growth both
like in the aesthetic stance like by
bringing more water into the muscles as
well like to make them look bigger for
that reason but also by verge of the
fact that it can improve exercise
performance it can help you get out more
reps and help you do more exercise and
in that regard lead to larger muscles as
well another really really solid
offering out there if you're looking for
the best creatine one to hydrate is huge
supplements creatine monohydrate right
that is called creatine it is creatine
monohydrate and it's another product
that is just straight up
creatine monohydrate with nothing else
added no Bells no whistles uh so we
think is another really really fantastic
option we also another really cool thing
about huge supplements is they offer
creating pills uh and they're like
they're very good value as well so we
don't know the best creatine pills at
that company they're really really solid
which is why we're doing with the best
creatine for bodybuilders as well
frankly
I prefer taking creatine capsules myself
it's just really easy to like put it in
with your other pills in the morning so
if you think about it you don't have to
go and get some water or anything to
wash it down with you need to go and get
a shaker cup you can have them when
you're out on the go you can have them
when you're out in the town when you're
at the gym itself it's a lot easier
you're not spilling it all over yourself
another thing everyone does that it's
not that complicated taking creatine but
creatine capsules is very easy if you
take daily pills your daily like
multivitamin your daily medications all
this sort of stuff you can just Chuck it
in there like in your little pill
capsule with everything else so that's
how I like to say creating myself and uh
because bodybuilders are generally
taking so many supplements throughout
the day having creatine in pill form
makes it a little bit easier and easier
to integrate it into one supplement
regimen and it's the ones day and one's
workouts then having loose padded
creatine all over the place so yeah huge
supplements very solid creatine pills
very good option of bodybuilders and a
very very good creature monohydrate now
I know I'm kind of throwing a lot of
information at you about creating and
about studies and that benefits and
ergogenic comments so if you would
rather ingest this content at your own
time at your own pace you're going to be
able to read what I'm saying instead of
watching me say it with this ridiculous
accent you can you can go to Google
right in bar Ben best creating and the
article version of this video will pop
right up so what's the best taste in
creating now creatine is flavorless
right so you can't really say it taste
good or bad it's like saying water
tastes good or bad but
you can flavor it very easily because it
has no taste this is in stock contrast
to other supplements like Branch chain
amino acids which when unflavored are
very very bitter and not very easy to
get down creatine is so flavorless you
can get a dent on its own just plain in
water it also makes it very easy to
carry just about any flavor you could
want to carry transparent Labs has this
really interesting product called
creatine hmb that we found to be the
best tasting one now again not super
hard to find a good tasting creatine
product because it's so easy to flavor
it doesn't have any uh conflicting
flavors coming back at you and uh
creatine hmb from transparent labs they
like took that and ran with it they just
gave a whole lot of flavors they've got
I think over 10 different flavors you
can get this in you've got sour grape
you've got a strawberry lemonade you've
got peach mango watermelon and they're
all absolutely delicious and also get
this naturally flavored and sweetened
which is very unusual in the world of
supplements but also honestly it stands
to reason it's a sensible thing to do
with creatine because it's so easy to
play creating again you kind of need
artificial sweeteners a lot of the time
with BCAAs uh not so creatine so this is
naturally flavored naturally sweetened
and the flavors of there are very many
flavors out there for this product and
they all taste really really good so in
addition to all those delicious flavors
we also think this the best for bulking
and not just because it has creatine
monohydrates because it's some
interesting additions to creatine hmb
that might give it an edge over other
creatine monohydrate products what we're
talking about here is hmb sensor hydroxy
methylbutyrate it is a metabolite found
in leucine amino acid closely associated
with muscle protein synthesis I know I'm
getting a little bit deep into the weeds
here but there are some limited research
who suggest that creatine when it's
combined with hmb maybe anti-catabolic
like so it can help to prevent muscle
breakdown and do so better than just
leucine on its own right leucine is the
main amino acid in Branch chain amino
acid supplements which a lot of people
take for enhancing the odds of muscle
retention when they're working out again
I'm getting a little bit too complicated
here but my point is hmb combined with
creatine appears to prevent muscle
breakdown better than creatine or hmb on
its own so deliveries are just pretty
limited but it's pretty interesting
stuff A lot of people are happy to pay
the extra to get some HIV what they're
creatine on top of that it has a vitamin
D in it as well vitamin D has pretty
interesting links with testosterone
production with Sleep Quality with burn
help all this stuff is of great interest
to folks who are bulking who are on the
bulk train so if you're looking for a
creatine that's good for bulking not
only does this have hmb it only does it
have vitamin D it also has black pepper
extract which may increase absorption so
all this together and all the delicious
flavors make scooping ancient bees
pretty solid buy coming up next the best
creatine for mixing the thing with
creation is if you ever put a scoop of
it into a glass of water it will fairly
quickly go and settle at the bottom and
then you know you drink it then you put
them a bit more water to mix it around
and get what's left at the bottom it can
be a little Annoying if that's something
you don't like micronized creatine is
probably the way they go so that's why
we've got the best creative mixing being
X wax lift xox pretty cool company a lot
of interesting supplements that
including some really interesting
carbohydrate supplements so the reason
we made Xbox the best great teams mixed
thing is because it's micronized
micronized particles up to 20 times
smaller than the particles of regular
creatine monohydrate they disperse more
easily and what after that's it that's
why that's the best creatine for mixing
also interestingly this bag here that
they decide to put it in a bag as
opposed to a jar and they're actually
cram in more creation than you normally
find so if your setting size is five
grams they're at 87s in this bag for
like roughly 50 bucks so it's pretty
economical as well it allows you to get
more creation than you normally can and
it's a it's like about 60 65 cents per
serving so in this climate because the
classic Creations increased a bit in the
last few years it's actually pretty good
especially has a lot of x-wife
supplements and surprisingly expensive
they creatine very reasonably priced all
right so what about the best pre-workout
with creatine you actually rarely see
pre-workouts with creatine in them at
least not at a decent dose and the fact
is you don't need to take creatine
before a workout as I mentioned you can
take it anytime day and just slowly your
muscles will saturate with creatine so
timing isn't really a big factor with it
nonetheless if you want a product I can
like put your creatine supplement and
your pre-workout supplement in together
to kill two birds with one Stern we like
pre-caged Elite from caged so this has
five grams of creatine in a scoop right
and they're actually interestingly two
different kinds of creatine you've got
creatine monohydrate of three grams and
two grams of creatine nitrate the only
real difference is creatine nitrates a
little more water-soluble uh it doesn't
really it's not really worth paying that
much extra attention to but still kind
of into the edge of creatine there
you're getting five grams but also a
pre-cage elite is one of the strongest
pre-workouts you're going to find uh
it's got 388 milligrams of caffeine in
one serving with those five grams of
creatine for context an average like 12
ounce cold brew from a coffee shop is
about 150 160 milligrams so this is more
than two cups of cold brew coffee at
once in addition to that it's got all
the other Mainstays you're going to get
at in pre-workouts like citrulline
beta-alanine betaing anhydrous
l-continental titrate and so on all of
them dosed at well above the minimum
effective dose suggested by research so
pre-workouts is obviously a totally
different subject with a lot to talk
about I encourage you to check out our
content on that but if you're looking
for a good pre-workout that has creatine
in it as long as you're happy to have
388 milligrams of caffeine along with it
I encourage you to check out
pre-caged then you get the area of
post-workout nutrition which is an
interesting one it doesn't get quite as
much attention as the pre-workout
supplements post workout people
generally talking about meals you should
be eating right but there are products
out there that focus on what to deliver
your body so that you can recover as
quickly and efficiently as you can from
workout right so our favorite one for
that is Formula 12 from huge supplements
the reason why we like this one is it
does have five grams of creatine
monohydrate right which makes it easy
it's also got a range of interesting
carbohydrates including cluster dextrin
which is intended to spike engine
deliberately in order to enhance
absorption of like the foods and the
other nutrients and ingredients in this
supplement right so it has a few
different types of carbohydrates in
there it also has plenty of ingredients
that are often found in pre-workouts now
without getting too deep into the weeds
here most ingredients in pre-workouts
like creatine you don't actually have to
have before a workout you can have it at
any time so there is beta alanine and
beta in anhydrous in here both of those
can improve workout performance neither
of which you have to take right before
workout as long as you've had them at
some point and with some regularity so a
bit of alanine can help with endurance
for your next workout bedding and
hydrants can help with power for your
next workout and so on and there's also
black pepper extract as well in here to
help with absorption so there's a few
interesting things going on here it's
kind of like a pre-workout minus the
caffeine plus some fast digesting and
slow adjusting carbohydrates help speed
along recovery interesting product and
if you're looking for one with a career
team does your best post workout
supplement with creating next up we're
going to investigate one of the more
unusual forms of creatine called
creatine hydrochloride it's kind of a
controversial addition in fact there are
some 10 different kinds of creatine out
there on the market and there are a lot
of companies trying to convince you that
this form or that form of creatine is
more effective uh the jury is still out
on most of them the vast majority of
research is on creatine monohydrate as a
safe effective and useful supplement
however there are plenty of people who
experience suggested distress with a
regular creation monohydrate and
creatine hydrochloride because it's
closer to the pH of our stomach maybe
easy to digest for those folks also the
serving size is smaller for creating
hydrochloride I guess more of it absorbs
or something so that's a bonus too while
you normally get five grams of creatine
monohydrate creating hydrochloride
you're normally taking 750 milligrams so
you get like a little teaspoon of it so
cage creatine hydrochloride is our pick
for this one uh it's fairly inexpensive
hydrochloride is more expensive than
monohydrate but this is still about 40
cents per gram and most hydrochlorides
out there are about 60 cents per grams
so this is very reasonably priced plus
they have added some flavoring to it a
nice lemon lime kind of flavor which is
tasty you can get unflavored if you want
or you can get it in pills you can get
all of these from caged and on top of
that they're all tested by informed
Choice which is a very important
third-party testing site to make sure
there are no banned substances or
anything like that so especially if
you're a competitive athlete and if
you're someone who wants to try out
hydrochloride this is a pretty good
option so next up is best creation for
beginners that's when we get asked a lot
to be clear playing old creatine
monohydrate is all you're really going
to get in a lot of supplements out there
but what we really like about bulk
supplements is they have a very
No-Frills approach to their stuff moons
and surprisingly even though they are
called bulk supplements you can get just
like 100 grams at a time so it's like 20
servings so that is just enough to get
you through the four weeks it's supposed
to take for your muscles to get fully
attached to the creatine so that's like
a really nice like uh amount of creatine
to buy at once and I would definitely
recommend you go out to box supplements
and then if you decide you like it you
can order hundreds and hundreds and
hundreds of servings at once if that's
the way you go and the more you get of
course the more money you save but for a
nice clean 100 gram amount of creatine
go to bug supplements it is nothing
about creatine monohydrate it's also
free from sugar soy Dairy yeast gluten
and additives and they run their own
Factory as well so it helps to uh
minimize the chance of
cross-contamination and that kind of
stuff if that's a big concern too bug
supplements you can get them in a bunch
of different sizes weigh more sizes you
can only get for any other company and
that's why it's best for beginners you
can get as much as you want you can get
the minimum amount to get the effects
lastly we're going to talk about best
creatine for women once again we don't
need to gender this stuff you can just
get regular creatine monohydrate however
we've found that our female readers are
often talking about Legion recharge
which might be giving away too much here
I like to have myself it's my favorite
way to have creatine because it's a
really delicious way to get your
creatine I like to come home from the
gym and pour a bunch of this into some
really really cold water it is really
refreshing because it has these really
nice flavors so there are several
flavors available from Legion and Legion
doesn't use any artificial flavors or
sweetness so that can be helpful for
women who are trying to avoid artificial
flavors so the sweeteners so this one
here's a strawberry lemonade flavor they
had a watermelon one that I had for many
years and they're just really nice and
refreshing to have after a workout but
what's also cool about this is that in
addition to having an artificial flavors
and also it's been delicious and also
having plenty of creatine in them
they've also got a couple of extra
goodies in here as well there's not a
lot the ingredients but there's got some
L-Carnitine El tartrate in this El
carnitine El tartrate has some
interesting research suggesting it may
be how helpful as part of a strategy to
try and have lean muscle and get rid of
as much fat as you can there's more to
it than that like your diet is like
vastly more important but nonetheless
there are some is there some research
suggesting that when other factors are
controlled for accounting Ultra it could
help to potentially boost the lean
muscle and fat loss component of a
workout plan so that's that's pretty
nice nice thrown there especially as a
post-workout drink and there's also a
bit of a chrysalic acid which is meant
to help to manage insulin sensitivity
there is pretty interesting research
suggestions they might potentially help
to give you an edge in your diet and
nutrition and workout plan as well so
yeah like there's pretty interesting
research to put in the other ingredients
too so that does it for our list of the
best creatine products uh before you go
out and buy creatine products just be
mindful of the fact that well I mean one
thing to remember is that a lot of
people try and convince you that there's
some new different weird type of
creatine that's more beneficial that's
better that's faster acting that has
more muscle growth the truth is creatine
monohydrate is the one that has had all
the research supporting it and these
other Niche new weird types of creatine
it's possible that one of them is better
but the research hasn't been done like
the vast majority of research has been
done just increasing you want to hydrate
the other ones have usually at best like
one or two studies on them so just to
create the amount of hydrate you're
going to be fine unless creatine is
difficult on your stomach in which case
creation had a chloride that's what has
the second most studies on it if you
have a more sensitive stomach when it
comes to creatine as far as loading it
you don't the the time of day you take
creatine doesn't matter it's not like a
pre-workout in that regard what most
people do is they learn they take five
grams per day and as I mentioned a few
times now after four weeks you're
saturated and you have uh all the
benefits you're going to get from
creating that doesn't mean you stop
taking it but yeah you just take five
grams a day there's no need to load it
like have a whole lot of creatine at
once uh it used to be the trend to have
like eight tablespoons a day and then
you stop taking creatine up like a week
or two uh but just just take five grams
a day you're gonna be fine
um another thing to note a local
electric cycle off creatine now and then
just just to give their body a rest
there's no real evidence that is bad for
you but nonetheless there's no reason to
not go off creatine them now and then
right so every few months like basically
just when I run out of a couple tubs of
creatine if I buy two I run out of them
I'll just take a break for a few weeks
just because like why not and then it's
like a nice bonus when you start taking
it again and your muscles get big again
but that's cycling off of creatine is a
thing that people often ask us about you
can if you want but it's it's not really
necessary and the last thing to do uh
with creatine monohydrate is toxiductor
before you start taking it or before you
start any new workout regimen or Diet
regimen or anything like that because
your doctor knows you better than we do
and can give you really individualized
advice to help you on your journey the
full article version of this video is on
Google Google bobbin best creatine
and I'm out I'm gonna wake up hope you
enjoyed this video see you in the next
one
thank you